

Curriculum Vitae for Sebastian Gjertsen

Personal information

Address: Rødstuveien E-mail: sebastian@xal.no

0572 Oslo Phone: 90804329

Born: 20.07.1990

Summary

I hold a masters degree in applied mathematics from the University of Oslo and Simula Research Labratory, finished in 2017. In my thesis I built a Fluid-Structure Interaction solver with Python using the FEniCS platform. This also included working with supercomputers parallelizing the computational efforts. During my studies I gained knowledge in algorithms, numerical computing and programming in different languages.

After graduating I worked for Shortcut AS, an app-development company, developing iOS apps and working with Splunk for monitoring and analyzing machine-generated big data. I have also taken courses and attended conferences on AI/Machine Learning, learning neural networks using Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn. Apart from that I am highly adaptable to any situation and can quickly learn new languages and frameworks.

Technical skills

Frameworks FEniCS, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas Languages Python, Swift, Java, C/C++

Tools Git, Splunk, VSTS

Education

2015 - 2017 Master in Applied Mathematics and Computational Science from the University of Oslo, Norway

2015 Exchange student at the University of Utrecth, Netherlands

2012 - 2015 Bachelor in Mathematics with Informatics from the University of Oslo,

Norway

Professional experience

2018 -	Expert Analytics AS
2017 - 2018	Shortcut AS
2014 - 2017	Mathematics and physics teacher while at University.
2013 - 2014	Sparebank 1
2011 - 2013	DNB

Languages

English Fluent, lived in the US for 2 years as a teenager.

Norwegian Native language

Personal skills

Machine learning

I have taken courses in machine learning, specifically learning about reccurent neural networks typically used for predicting timeseries data, convolutional neural networks most often used for image recognition, and also other methods for tackling classification and regression problems.

I have also learned to setup recommender systems which is used to predict a user's ratings or of preference to an item, famously used by companies like Netflix, last.fm, LinkedIn and Facebook. I was involved in the initial phases of setting up such a recommender system for a client.

Whilst learning about machine learning I have used frameworks and languages such as TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, Pandas, Python and Matlab. Course certificate: https://www.coursera.org/account/

accomplishments/certificate/EHGJT2SFVHVK.

Programming I am most familiar with Python because of the extensive use in my

> studies, but I also have an understanding of Java, C/C++. While working as an app developer I also gained knowledge of Swift and Objective-C. I love programming and I am always interested in, and consider myself quickly adaptable to, new programming languages. In my studies and in my working experience I have used GitHub and I

am familiar with agile software development.

Some interests and hobbies

Ice-Hockey I played Ice-hockey throughout my youth, and lived 2 years in Min-

nesota, USA playing and attending high school. Now I play somewhat

frequently with a lower division team in Oslo.

Music Most of my time spent outside of work is playing guitar. I play in a

band which plays original music and gigs often around Oslo. I also play

in different projects with singers, dis etc.

expertanalytics.no

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity REMA1000, Æ app with over 1 million users.

Role Splunk Coordinator, iOS developer

Staffing Shortcut, Bouvet, Communicate, SopraSteria, Stix, Verifone and Vis-

ma

Description Æ is an app by REMA1000 to help consumers save money and keep

track of their purchases. My job was to use the Splunk tool to overview the API calls made by the app to several endpoints, and to set up automatic alarm systems to warn for excessive error codes. I also

worked as a iOS developer on this project.

Tools Splunk

Activity Fluid-Structure Interaction solver built in Python using FEniCS

Staffing 1 researcher, Simula Research Laboratory

Description My master thesis consisted of building a Fluid-Structure Interaction

solver, which can by used to model for instance blood flowing in arteries or oil flowing in a pipe. This solver was built to not only consider the flowing of a fluid but also the displacement of a structure interacting with the fluid. The solver was written in Python using the FEniCS

framework.